Guide to the Elsa Guerdrum Allen papers, 1885-1976,
Allen, Elsa Guerdrum papers, 1885-1976
- Series III. Research and Manuscripts by Elsa Allen
  - Bird Poetry
    - Birds in Literature: Bibliographic Notes and Rough Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 15)
    - Birds in Literature, undated (Box 10, Folder 16)
    - Bird Poetry and Notes on Early American Literature, undated (Box 10, Folder 17)
    - Bird Poetry (1), undated (Box 10, Folder 18)
      Folder marked "Rough Draft - English Thesis" but the thesis is not inside.
    - Bird Poetry (2), undated (Box 10, Folder 19)
      Folder marked "English Thesis 2nd Carbon" but the thesis is not inside.
    - Bird Poetry (3) - Loose, undated (Box 10, Folder 20)
      Loose in Box
    - Bird Poetry - Thrushes, undated (Box 10, Folder 21)
    - Bird Poetry - Catbirds, Mockingbirds, Wrens, Nuthatches and Titmice, undated (Box 10, Folder 22)
    - Bird Poetry - Sparrows, Finches, Grosbeaks, Crossbills and Buntings, undated (Box 10, Folder 23)
    - Bird Poetry - Herons, Ibises, Cranes, Gallinules, Coots, Sandpipers and Plovers, undated (Box 10, Folder 24)
      "Birds of the Shores and Marshes"
    - Bird Poetry - Turkeys, Grouse, Quail, Partridge, Pigeons and Doves, undated (Box 10, Folder 25)
      "Gallinaceous Birds"
    - Bird Poetry - Vultures, Hawks, and Owls, undated (Box 10, Folder 26)
      "Predaceous Birds"
    - Bird Poetry - Flycatchers, :arks, Crows, Jays and Blackbirds, undated (Box 10, Folder 27)
    - Bird Poetry - Cuckoos, Kingfishers, Woodpeckers, Nighthawks, Whip-poor-wills, Swifts and Hummingbirds, undated (Box 10, Folder 28)
    - Bird Poetry - Tanagers, Swallows, Waxwings, Vireos and Warblers, undated (Box 10, Folder 29)
    - Bird Poetry - Birds General, undated (Box 10, Folder 30)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript, undated (Box 10, Folder 31)
      Found with American Ornithology Before Audubon Manuscript and Loose pages of Chipmunk Study manuscript
    - Bird Poetry Manuscript and Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 32)
    - Notes on Bird Poetry, undated (Box 10, Folder 33)
    - Bird Poetry Manuscript with Notes on Particular Species, c. 1930 (Box 10, Folder 34)
    - Birds and Poets: Copies of Poems and Loose Pages of Manuscript, undated (Box 10, Folder 35)
    - Collected Early American Poetry on Birds (1), undated (Box 10, Folder 36)
    - Collected Early American Poetry on Birds (2), undated (Box 10, Folder 37)
  - Alexander Wilson
    - Alexander Wilson Notes and Correspondence, 1948-1950 (Box 10, Folder 38)
      Correspondence Regarding Alexander, Wilson notes and "The Paisley Memorials to Alexander Wilson" by Elsa Allen
    - Alexander Wilson Research, undated (Box 10, Folder 39)
      Includes parts of the manuscript
    - "The American Ornithology" regarding Alexander Wilson, undated (Box 10, Folder 40)
    - Sections from Alexander Wilson Manuscript, undated (Box 10, Folder 41)
      Handwritten and typed
    - Alexander Wilson Manuscript, undated (Box 10, Folder 42)
      Parts used for The History of American Ornithology?
    - Early Draft of Article on Wilson and on the Wilson Monument in Indiana, undated (Box 10, Folder 43)
    - The American Career of Alexander Wilson, undated (Box 10, Folder 44)
      Also "The Schoolmaster at Gray's Ferry"
    - The American Career of Alexander Wilson - Early Draft, undated (Box 10, Folder 45)
    - Manuscript on Alexander Wilson and Bird Literature, undated (Box 10, Folder 46)
    - Wilson as a Poet and Biographical Notes, undated (Box 10, Folder 47)
  - The History of American Ornitholgy Before Audubon
    - A - Audubon, [1896]1935-1955 (Box 11, Folder 1)
      Includes research on Audubon as well as correspondence with Waldemar Fries about purchasing ornithology works including an Audubon Elephant Edition. Also includes a small volume entitled "Little Journeys to the Homes of American Authors: Audubon by Parke Godwin, August 1896
    - Notes and Handwritten Sections of Chapters, undated (Box 11, Folder 2)
    - Pages on Scientific Societies and Collections of Rarities, undated (Box 11, Folder 3)
      The title page for "Minerva's Daughters" by Elsa Allen was also found here
    - George Edwards Subtractions, undated (Box 11, Folder 4)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript and Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 5)
    - List of Slides Received from Gordon Dunthorne Regarding the History of Ornithology, undated (Box 11, Folder 7)
    - Bibliography and footnotes, undated (Box 11, Folder 6)
    - Script for a Radio Talk, March 04, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 8)
    - Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 9)
    - Bird Lore, Old and New, undated (Box 11, Folder 10)
      Typed and handwritten manuscript
    - Notes and Sections of Several Chapters, undated (Box 11, Folder 11)
    - Sections of Several Chapters, undated (Box 11, Folder 12)
      Typed and handwritten manuscript found with correspondence from the 1930s
    - Sections of Several Chapters, undated (Box 11, Folder 13)
      Typed manuscript found with correspondence from the 1930s
    - Sections of Several Chapters, undated (Box 11, Folder 14)
      Typed and handwritten manuscript: Includes "Jacques Le Moyne: First Zoological Artist in America" by Elsa Allen for the Auk
    - Sections of Several Chapters (1), undated (Box 11, Folder 15)
      Typed and handwritten manuscript: Includes sections on George Edwards, Thomas Pennant and John Letham
    - Sections of Several Chapters (2), undated (Box 11, Folder 16)
    - Sections of Several Chapters, undated (Box 11, Folder 17)
      Typed and handwritten manuscript: Includes Thomas Jefferson, Minor Bird Lists of the Latter 18th Century, Title Page and Dedication to Arthur Allen
    - Sections of Chapter VII, undated (Box 11, Folder 18)
      Handwritten manuscript: Includes John Clayton, John Lawson, John Bricksell, John Josselyn. Note reads "Taken out for corrections"
    - Introduction and Chapter I, undated (Box 11, Folder 19)
      Typed manuscript
    - Several Versions of an Abstraction of the Book (Pages 1-49), undated (Box 11, Folder 20)
    - European Ornithologists and Early Bird Lore in the Western World, undated (Box 11, Folder 21)
    - Notes - Mainly on State Histories, undated (Box 11, Folder 22)
    - Revision Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 23)
    - Notes and Handwritten Pages of Manuscript, undated (Box 11, Folder 24)
    - The Encyclopedists, undated (Box 11, Folder 25)
    - Modern Period, undated (Box 11, Folder 26)
    - Peter Kalm Notes, undated (Box 11, Folder 27)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 11, Folder 28)
    - John Josselyn, David Crantz, and Hans Egede, undated (Box 11, Folder 29)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 11, Folder 30)
      Includes portions of a grant application from 1932
    - Chapter IX, undated (Box 11, Folder 31)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 11, Folder 32)
      "Carbons"
    - American Philosophical Society Article, 1938 (Box 11, Folder 33)
      "Possible revise this article into a popular book"
    - Sections of Chapter 9 and Revisions, undated (Box 11, Folder 34)
    - Sections of Chapter 11 and Revisions, undated (Box 11, Folder 35)
    - Sections of Chapter 8 - Mark Catesby, George Edwards and others, undated (Box 11, Folder 36)
    - Sections of Chapter 6 - Early Colonial Period, undated (Box 11, Folder 37)
    - Sections of Chapter 2 - Aristotle and Medieval, undated (Box 11, Folder 38)
    - Sections of Several Chapters, List of Illustrations, undated (Box 11, Folder 39)
    - Sections of Several Different Manuscript Chapters (1), undated (Box 11, Folder 40)
      In Folder Marked Miscellaneous Carbons
    - Sections of Several Different Manuscript Chapters (2), undated (Box 11, Folder 41)
    - "Doctor Volcher Coiter, 1534-1576: A North Aolland Scholar of the 16th Century", undated (Box 11, Folder 42)
    - Handwritten Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 11, Folder 43)
      Includes Thomas Pennant, William Bartram, George Edwards and John White
    - Introduction to Beginnings of American Ornithology, undated (Box 11, Folder 44)
    - Correspondence between Baird, Spencer and Brewer, T.M. and D.D. Stone, 1879 (Box 11, Folder 45)
      For second volume of the History of American Ornithology
    - Loose handwritten notes for John Abbot of Georgia and The History of American Ornithology Before Audubon - found as is, undated (Box 11, Folder 46)
      Also includes a letter regarding Signe Bartsch
    - Title Page and Old Introduction (not used), undated (Box 12, Folder 1)
    - Sections of Several Chapters, undated (Box 12, Folder 2)
    - Sections on William Bartram and Louis Jean Pierre Vieillot, undated (Box 12, Folder 3)
      Typed and Handwritten Manuscript
    - Bibliography, undated (Box 12, Folder 4)
      Typed Manuscript
    - Section on Louis Jean Pierre Vieillot and Alexander Wilson, undated (Box 12, Folder 5)
    - Early Version of Chapter 1, Acknowledgements - Ancient Beginnings of Ornithology, undated (Box 12, Folder 6)
    - Sections on William Bartram, William Catesby, Peter Kahn and Alexander Wilson, undated (Box 12, Folder 7)
      Typewritten Manuscript
    - Ornithology Notes, Bird Poetry, Volcher Coiter and Alexander Wilson, undated (Box 12, Folder 8)
    - Samuel Hearne Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 9)
    - Preface, undated (Box 12, Folder 10)
    - Loose Notes and Pages, undated (Box 12, Folder 11)
    - Handwritten Draft of Sections of Several Chapters. Including Aristotle, Averroes, and Medieval, undated (Box 12, Folder 12)
    - Handwritten and Typed Sections of Several Chapters and Notes. Includes Louis Jean Pierre Vieillot, Jean Baptiste Audebert and Johann Reinhold Forster, undated (Box 12, Folder 13)
    - "The First Apostle of The Living Bird" Notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 14)
      William Bartram
    - List of Illustrations that are NOT enclosed., undated (Box 12, Folder 15)
    - Early Bird Lore in England, undated (Box 12, Folder 16)
      Handwritten manuscript
    - Sir Thomas Browne, Christopher Merrit, William Turner, John Ray and Francis Willoughby, undated (Box 12, Folder 17)
      Copies and typed manuscript
    - The Rise of the Experimental Method in the Middle Ages, undated (Box 12, Folder 18)
      Note by Elsa Allen "Historical"
    - "Glimpses of American Ornithology Before Audubon" by Elsa Allen, undated (Box 12, Folder 19)
    - Early Chapters on John White and Jacques LeMoyne; Research Notes; and Correspondence, c. 1935-1949 (Box 12, Folder 20)
      Typed and handwritten manuscript: Includes clippings regarding the early settlement of Virginia and Alexander Wilson
    - Two Early Drafts of Title Pages, undated (Box 12, Folder 21)
    - Loose pages of research notes, undated (Box 12, Folder 22)
    - Write Ups Regarding Research Projects, undated (Box 12, Folder 23)
      "A Declaration of the Reasons for Believing the Proposed Book to be Needed," a Deleted Section of the Manuscript, and a Transcript of a Radio Talk
    - Chapter on Early England, undated (Box 12, Folder 24)
    - Old Carbons - Sections of Several Chapters, c. 1949 (Box 12, Folder 25)
    - Ancient Bird Lore, undated (Box 12, Folder 26)
    - Draft of Chapter I, undated (Box 12, Folder 27)
    - "Early Work on Before Audubon", [1933-1939] (Box 12, Folder 28)
      Typed and handwritten manuscript: Includes correspondence from 1935-1939
    - Introduction, Acknowledgements, Table of Contents and List of Illustrations, undated (Box 12, Folder 29)
    - Bibliography (Incomplete), undated (Box 12, Folder 30)
    - Loose Pages of Notes and Clippings, undated (Box 12, Folder 31)
    - Section of Chapter on Louis Jean Pierre Vieillot, undated (Box 12, Folder 32)
    - Loose Notes and Handwritten Manuscript Pages, undated (Box 12, Folder 34)
    - Notes on Volcher Coiter, undated (Box 12, Folder 35)
    - Loose Handwritten and Typed Pages, undated (Box 12, Folder 36)
    - Handwritten Sections of Several Chapters, undated (Box 12, Folder 37)
    - Handwritten Manuscript for "The Early Ornithological Work of Hudson Bay and Other Boreal Regions", undated (Box 12, Folder 38)
    - Notes on the Voyages of Captain James Cook, undated (Box 12, Folder 39)
    - The Old Version of Section on Ulisse Aldrovandus, undated (Box 12, Folder 40)
    - Handwritten and Typed Sections of Several Chapters -, undated (Box 12, Folder 41)
    - Alexander Wilson and His Relationship with Audubon, undated (Box 12, Folder 42)
    - Section on Norsemen, undated (Box 12, Folder 43)
    - Section on Francisco Clavijero, undated (Box 12, Folder 44)
    - London Notes, 1934-1935 (Box 12, Folder 45)
    - Early Version of First few Chapters, undated (Box 12, Folder 46)
    - Chapter 2 - Old Version, undated (Box 12, Folder 47)
    - Final Revision - Loose Pages (1), undated (Box 12, Folder 48)
    - Final Revision - Loose Pages (2), undated (Box 13, Folder 49)
    - Final Revision - Loose Pages (3), undated (Box 13, Folder 50)
      Some pages have flags for editing which have been folded
    - Final Revision - Loose Pages (4), undated (Box 13, Folder 51)
    - Corrections to Manuscript, undated (Box 13, Folder 52)
    - "Items to be Checked in Before Audubon", 1951-1953 (Box 12, Folder 53)
    - University of Chicago Press, undated (Box 12, Folder 54)
    - Proposal for Second Volume of The History of Ornithology, undated (Box 12, Folder 55)
    - Handwritten and Typed Notes for the 2nd Volume of The History of American Ornithology Before Audubon, undated (Box 12, Folder 56)
    - Correspondence found in The History of American Ornithology Before Audubon Materials, undated (Box 12, Folder 57)
    - Notes, Outline and Section Marked Pages 65-113, undated (Box 12, Folder 58)
    - Galley Proof - Pages 1-54, undated (Box 13, Folder 1)
    - Galley Proof - Pages 55-136, undated (Box 13, Folder 2)
    - Galley Proof - Bibliography, undated (Box 13, Folder 3)
    - Author's Page Proof of Book: Page 386 (Title Page) - 500, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 4)
    - Author's Page Proof of Book: Page 501-569, 1951 (Box 13, Folder 5)
    - Galley Proof for Illustrations, Bibliography and Index, undated (Box 13, Folder 6)
    - Final Draft: Introduction, Table of Content, Chapter 1 and 2 - pages 1-85 (skips 20-31) and footnotes for Chapter 2, undated (Box 13, Folder 7)
    - Chapter 3 and 4, pages 86-193 and footnotes, undated (Box 13, Folder 8)
      Final Draft
    - Chapter 5, pages 194-270, undated (Box 13, Folder 9)
    - Chapter 6, pages 271-321, undated (Box 13, Folder 10)
    - Chapter 7, pages 322-364, undated (Box 13, Folder 11)
    - Chapter 8, pages 365-425 and footnotes, undated (Box 13, Folder 12)
    - Chapter 9, pages 426-522 and footnotes, undated (Box 13, Folder 13)
    - Chapter 10, 523-568 and footnotes, undated (Box 13, Folder 14)
    - Chapter 11, 569-628 and footnotes, undated (Box 13, Folder 15)
    - Chapter 12, pages 629-691 and footnotes, undated (Box 13, Folder 16)
    - Chapter 13, pages 692-753 and footnotes, undated (Box 13, Folder 17)
    - Chapter 14, pages 754-825 and footnotes, undated (Box 13, Folder 18)
    - Bibliography, pages 826-868, undated (Box 13, Folder 19)
    - Index, undated (Box 13, Folder 20)
    - Title Page-7 and Pages 48-162 (Chapter III), undated (Box 13, Folder 21)
      Note reads that Chapter 1 and 2 are missing
    - Chapter IV-V, undated (Box 13, Folder 22)
    - Chapter VI-VII, undated (Box 13, Folder 23)
    - Chapter VIII, undated (Box 13, Folder 24)
    - Chapter IX, undated (Box 13, Folder 25)
      Includes notes and rewrites
    - Chapter X (pages 486-599), undated (Box 13, Folder 26)
    - Chapter X (pages 600-681), undated (Box 13, Folder 27)
    - Dent Collection for the Second Volume - Post Audubon, undated (Box 13, Folder 28)
    - Book Jacket of "Titian Ramsay Peale 1799-1885: And His Journals of the Wilkes Expedition, undated (Box 13, Folder 29)
    - Introduction, Illustrations, Table of Contents and Chapter 1 and 2, undated (Box 13, Folder 30)
    - Handwritten Outline and Section on John Abbot, undated (Box 13, Folder 31)
      Envelope is from American Philosophical Society, 1951 Printer's Proof
  - John Abbot of Georgia
    - Savannah, Georgia, October, 1954 (Box 3)
    - Abbot Notes, June and October, 1952 (Box 3)
      Notebook: Pittsburg Manuscript owned by Avinoff
    - Sections from Several Chapters including Directions for Reading the Tabulation, Introduction, and Footnotes, undated (Box 14, Folder 1)
    - Footnotes, undated (Box 14, Folder 2)
    - Original John Abbot Manuscript and directions for reading tablature of Chapter 18 (1), undated (Box 14, Folder 3)
    - Original John Abbot Manuscript (2), undated (Box 14, Folder 4)
    - Copies of John Abbot Legal Papers for 1787, 1820 and 1822, undated (Box 14, Folder 5)
      Includes gift of slaves to his daughter Elisa
    - Copies of Legal Papers Re: John Abbot, undated (Box 14, Folder 6)
      Includes John Abbot Jr. trial for killing his slave
    - Photocopies of John Abbot correspondence to Henrich Escher, undated (Box 14, Folder 7)
      Research
    - John Eatton LeConte Notes and Correspondence, undated (Box 14, Folder 8)
    - Illustrations, List of Photographs and Part of Chapter One, undated (Box 14, Folder 9)
    - Several Manuscript Chapters, Introduction and Appendices of John Abbot Manuscript and Correspondence, undated (Box 14, Folder 10)
      Includes a rejection letter from the Cornell University Press, 1965 and a reprint of a summary of the Abbot project for a grant given by the American Philosophical Society
    - Sections of Footnotes and Correspondence, undated (Box 14, Folder 11)
    - Chapter XII - Abbot's Spiders, undated (Box 14, Folder 12)
      Early version of Manuscript
    - Early John Abbot Manuscript, undated (Box 14, Folder 13)
      "Early and not good probably should be destroyed"
    - Description of the John Eatton LeConte Drawings at the American Philosophical Society, undated (Box 14, Folder 14)
    - Copies of deeds for a different John Abbot, undated (Box 14, Folder 15)
    - Transcript of Volume 1 of John Abbot Bird Drawings at the British Museum, undated (Box 14, Folder 16)
      2 Copies
    - Copy of "Drawings and Natural History of the Birds of Georgia, in America" by John Abbot, undated (Box 14, Folder 17)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript, Notes and Correspondence, undated (Box 14, Folder 19)
    - Two photos of illustrations by unknown artists and an outline of the Appendices for John Abbot, undated (Box 14, Folder 20)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters: Chapters IV-VIII, undated (Box 14, Folder 21)
    - Revisions - Sections of Several Chapters, Research Materials and Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 22)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 14, Folder 23)
    - Research Notes and Sections of Several Chapters, undated (Box 14, Folder 24)
      Mainly notes on Illustrations
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 14, Folder 25)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters and Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 26)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters and Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 27)
    - Sections of Preface, Acknowledgements, and Chapter 8, undated (Box 14, Folder 28)
    - Introductory Matter - Title Page, Acknowledgements, Dedication and Section of Chapter 7, undated (Box 14, Folder 29)
    - Loose Manuscript Sections and Notes (1), undated (Box 14, Folder 30)
    - Handwritten Sheets from the Original Manuscript, undated (Box 14, Folder 31)
    - Small Private Collections of Abbot Drawings, 1934-1959 (Box 14, Folder 32)
      Marion Carson, Josephine Henry, Emma Hartridge, DeLoach, R.J.H.
    - Mayr, Ernst - Museum of Comparative Zoology Harvard University, 1957 (Box 14, Folder 33)
      Includes handwritten and typed notes for John Abbot Memorial Lecture
    - National Archives, 1955-1957 (Box 14, Folder 34)
      Includes Typewritten notes on John Abbot
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 14, Folder 35)
      Typed and handwritten
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 14, Folder 36)
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 14, Folder 37)
    - Sections from Several Manuscript Chapters and Research Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 38)
    - Sections from Several Manuscript Chapters, undated (Box 14, Folder 39)
    - Loose Manuscript Sections and Research Notes, undated (Box 14, Folder 40)
      Includes some correspondence and notes from Set 7 at the National Museum in Washington D.C.
    - Sections of Several Manuscript Chapters, Notes and Correspondence, undated (Box 14, Folder 41)
    - Loose Pages of Manuscript and Research Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 42)
    - Copies of John Abbot's Letters to Swainson in Elsa Allen's Handwriting, c. 1948 (Box 15, Folder 1)
      Letter found in the collection of the Linnaean Society, London
    - Preface, Chapters III and IV, undated (Box 15, Folder 2)
      Manuscript: Missing Chapter I and II
    - Chapter V-XVIII and Footnotes, undated (Box 15, Folder 3)
    - Section on Jean Louis LeConte, undated (Box 15, Folder 4)
      Manuscript: In a folder marked "Catesby"
    - Loose Manuscript Pages, undated (Box 15, Folder 5)
      Includes Contents and part of a List of Illustrations
    - Correspondence and Research Notes Regarding Illustrations and a Portrait of John Abbot, undated (Box 15, Folder 6)
    - Chart of the Locations of John Abbot Drawings, undated (Box 15, Folder 7)
    - Savannah, Georgia, February, 1956 (Box 15, Folder 8)
    - Manchester and Berlin, 1953 (Box 15, Folder 9)
    - Notes, undated (Box 15, Folder 10)
    - Notes Regarding Set 5 of John Abbot Drawings from Knowsley Hall, undated (Box 15, Folder 11)
    - Notes and Correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 12)
    - Revisions - Sections from Several Chapters - Handwritten and Typed, undated (Box 15, Folder 13)
    - Research Notes on John Abbot Drawings, undated (Box 15, Folder 14)
      Torn from a notebook - "I kept my Knowsley notebook in my other bag and brought my briefcase here. What a dope. So now I must use this."
    - John Abbot Lecture: Nashville and Savannah, 1957 (Box 15, Folder 15)
    - Correspondence and loose pages of manuscript regarding John Eaton LeConte, c. 1958 (Box 15, Folder 16)
    - Chapters on the Lesser Black woodpecker and Abbot's Drawings of Spiders, undated (Box 15, Folder 17)
    - List of Plates, undated (Box 15, Folder 18)
    - Loose Research Notes on John Abbot, undated (Box 15, Folder 19)
    - Loose Sections of Various Chapters, undated (Box 15, Folder 20)
    - Chapter XII and Loose Sections, undated (Box 15, Folder 21)
    - Chapter VIII - Abbot's Published Work, undated (Box 15, Folder 22)
    - Outline of Abbot Lecture and Research Notes on a Set of Abbot Drawings at the British Museum, undated (Box 15, Folder 23)
    - Chapter XV, XX and Part of Acknowledgements, undated (Box 15, Folder 24)
    - Chapter VI and V and Loose Sections, undated (Box 15, Folder 25)
    - Various Notes and Loose pages of Manuscript, undated (Box 15, Folder 26)
      Folder reads "Rare and Vanished Birds" but that material seems to have been moved.
    - Sections of Several Chapters, Title Page and Table of Contents, undated (Box 15, Folder 27)
    - Conclusion Notes: Groups of Abbot Drawings and Section on Abbot Trail, undated (Box 15, Folder 28)
    - Emory and English Albums of Abbot Drawings, undated (Box 15, Folder 29)
    - Chapter IV - John Eatton LeConte, undated (Box 15, Folder 30)
    - Joseph Vallence Bevan Bibliography, undated (Box 15, Folder 31)
    - Richard Sparrow Redman - Copies of Will and Correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 32)
    - Preface, undated (Box 15, Folder 33)
    - Preface, Chapter 1, 2, & 3 Marked for Changes and Correspondence, undated (Box 15, Folder 34)
    - Loose Notes and Pages, undated (Box 15, Folder 35)